A Guide to the St. James Parish (Mecklenburg County, Va.) records, 1863-2011
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
St. James Parish (Mecklenburg County, Va.) records, 1863-2011
The Library of Virginia
50536
2.55 cu. ft. and 4 boxes and 2 volumes
St. James Parish (Mecklenburg County, Va.)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Christine H. Park of Boydton.
Alternative Form Available
Use Miscellaneous microfilm reels 6132-6133.
Scope and Content
Records, 1863-2011, of St. James Parish in Mecklenburg County, Virginia, consisting of registers, 1863-2011, containing information on baptisms, confirmations, communion, weddings, and burials for St. James', St. Timothy's, St. Luke's, St. John's (Old Church), Grace, St. Andrew's, Christ Chapel, and Central Mecklenburg Cure churches. Also contains a vestry book, 1965-2010, for St. James Church; minute book, 1889-1896, of the Ambler Missionary Society; minute book, 1894-1902, of the St. James Branch, Woman's Auxiliary of the Board of Missions; St. James Fellowship treasurer's book, 1958-1967; and a study of the Episcopal Church in the Diocese of Southern Virginia, SV 38 Christ Chapel, Boydton, Virginia. Collection also includes loose papers, including histories of the churches, correspondence, clippings, bulletins, photographs, and other papers related to the Episcopal churches in Mecklenburg County. Collection includes photostat copies of the St. James Parish register, 1869-1926 and the St. Luke's, St. Timothy's and Old Church (St. John's) parish register. The original volumes are located in this collection and have been microfilmed from these originals. The photostat copies have not been microfilmed.
Contents List
- St. James Parish register, 1869-1926 (Box 1)
- St. James Parish register, 1869-1880 (Box 1)
- St. James Church parish register, 1948-1988 (Box 1)
- St. James Church parish register, 1984-2000 (Box 1)
- St. James Church register of church services, 1951-1971 (Box 1)
- St. James Church register of church services, 2001-2011 (Box 2)
- St. Luke's, St. Timothy's, and St. John's (Old Church) Churches parish register, 1863-1907 (Box 2)
- St. Luke's, St. Timothy's, St. John's (Old Church), and Grace Church parish register, 1910-1944 (Box 2)
- Christ Chapel parish register, 1927-1981 (Box 2)
- Christ Chapel parish register, 1965-1990 (Box 2)
- Central Mecklenburg Cure parish register, 1985-2011 (Box 3)
- Ambler Missionary Society minute book, 1889-1896 (Box 3)
- St. James' Branch of the Woman's Auxiliary to the Board of Missions minute book, 1894-1902 (Box 3)
- St. James Fellowship treasurer's book, 1958-1967 (Box 3)
- Loose papers found in parish records, 1901-1959 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Items found loose in church books (histories), no date (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Items found loose in church books (correspondence), 1954-2000, no date (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Items found loose in church books (clippings), 1987-1997, no date (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Items found loose in church books (miscellaneous), 1967-2009, no date (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Personal papers of Dr. Shelton H. Short, III (Box 3, Folder 6)
- St. James Church parish register, 1926-1948 (Box 4)
- A Study of the Episcopal Church in the Diocese of Southern Virginia--SV 38 Christ Chapel, Boydton (Box 4)
- St. James Church vestry minute book, 1965-2010 (Volume on shelf)